MICHAEL ACORD

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

acordmike@gmail.com 1-920-224-4584 https://www.mikeacord.com

Senior full-stack software engineer with 14 years' experience developing leading-edge technologies. Passionate developer with demonstrated leadership abilities and excellent communication skills. Expert in all aspects of the software life cycle, from specification through analysis and design, to testing maintenance and evaluation of the product.

SKILLS

WEB JAVASCRIPT HTML 5 CSS LAMP MVC REST CSS

JAVASCRIPT ANGULAR.JS JQUERY BACKBONE.JS

DATABASE SQL SERVER TSQL INTEGRATION SERVICES ANALYSIS SERVICES REPORTING SERVICES

CLOUD AZURE

PROJECT AGILE TFS

DEVOPS TFS TEAM CITY OCTOPUS DEPLOY

SHAREPOINT ADMINISTRATION DEVELOPMENT OFFICE 365

EMPLOYMENT

Senior Solutions Architect, Consultant, Omni Resources

2012-07 — Present

Building leading-edge solutions for clients Provided guidance and leadership to new employees

- Implemented Office 365, saving Omni \$5K/year in email hosting costs
- Managed internal VMWare infrastructure
- Lead development of internal project reporting application
- Developed continuous deployment of internal applications using TeamCity and Octopus Deploy
- Introduced and administered common team tools, including TFS, Slack and a team Wiki

Agile C# DevOps JavaScript AngularJS jQuery ASP.Net MVC SQL Server Octopus Deploy Azure TeamCity Office 365 TFS Administration

Consultant, Insurance Company Designed and developed new data warehouse

2015-01 — Present

- Modeled Operational Store (ODS) and Data Warehouse (DW)
- Developed ETL templates for incrementally loading data
- Built ETL routines to load data into the DW from multiple data sources

Agile AWS SQL Server Redshift TSQL Data Warehousing ETL SSIS Power Designer

Consultant, Medical Outcome Reporting Company Led team to develop a flexible interview building and reporting application

2015-01 - 2015-01

Designed and implemented custom interview building designer

- Designed and built flexible reporting of interview responses
- Implemented continuous integration and deployment pipeline using TeamCity and Octopus

Agile C# ASP.Net MVC AngularJS JavaScript Azure SQL Server DevOps TeamCity Octopus Deploy

Team lead and architect for a custom-built reporting module to a Student Management System

Consultant, Student Management System Company

2014-01 - 2015-01

• Designed and developed streaming report execution engine Led team of developers building simple but powerful web-based WYSIWYG report editor

• Developed report rendering engine to allow delivery of reports in multiple formats

Agile C# JavaScript jQuery ASP.Net MVC SQL Server Responsive Design

Consultant, Sporting Vehicle Dealership Software Company Developed company's next-generation dealership showcase website

2012-01 - 2013-01

- Developed Azure storage services to save and retrieve custom images Designed and implemented common exception handling pattern
- Maintained greater than 90% code coverage
- Developed content modules for use in custom-build CMS System
- Agile C# JavaScript BackboneJS Azure Web Services SQL Server Responsive Design

SharePoint/Business Intelligence Technical Lead / Consultant, 2008-06 - 2012-06

Heartland Business Systems (Avastone) Designed and developed custom .Net, Business Intelligence and SharePoint solutions for businesses,

managed technical consulting team Managed team of SharePoint and BI Consultants Developed school teacher evaluation system in SharePoint, .Net and JavaScript

- Created health reporting and analytics system in ASP.Net MVC
- Designed and created school district website in SharePoint
- Developed new product workflow application in InfoPath
- Designed and developed a data warehouse on SQL Server database and Analysis Services
- Implemented numerous SharePoint installations, upgrades and custom development projects
- C# JavaScript ASP.Net MVC SQL Server Analysis Services Integration Services Sharepoint Business

Intelligence **Business Intelligence Consultant, Fujitsu Consulting** 2006-08 - 2008-04

Senior BI Consultant building data integration solutions • Designed and developed data migration strategy from legacy system using Integration Services

Created real-time data integration from new web application back to legacy mainframe

 Developed reporting services reports Designed and optimized data access strategy

2005-05 - 2006-07

Business Intelligence Consultant, Compuware SQL Server development consulting

SSIS SQL Server ASP.Net C# Reporting Services TSQL

Developed bill of materials cost reporting application in MS Access

Developed and optimized SQL Server applications

SQL Server MS Access Crystal Reports

• Developed Crystal Reports

Systems Analyst, DRS Power and Control Technologies

2001-08 - 2005-08

Internal application development and support Created an Operational Data Store from mainframe data

- Created Crystal Reports to the analyze business data
- Gathered and analyzed business requirements SQL Server DTS ASP VB.Net ASP.Net TSQL Crystal Reports

Led cross-functional, multi-site teams to facilitate and improve business processes

EDUCATION

Milwaukee School of Engineering

MS in Management-Electronic Business, University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee

2002-08 - 2003-12

BS in Business and Computer Systems, International Business,

1998-08 - 2002-05